<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/cms/system/modules/org.tei.www/_common/schemas/teilite.rnc" type="compact"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" rend="home">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>TEI Manuscripts Special Interest Group</title>
                <author>Susan Schreibman, Elena Pierazzo, Edward Vanhoutte</author>
                <sponsor>TEI-C</sponsor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>TEI-C</publisher>
                <distributor>TEI-C</distributor>
                <authority>TEI-C</authority>
                <pubPlace>Gent (Belgium)</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Created in electronic format</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2018-01-11" who="KSH">removed link to
                http://www.tei-c.org/SIG/Manuscripts/, which will be deleted</change>
            <change when="2017-11-18" who="KSH">new co-convenor</change>
            <change when="2013-03-07" who="KSH">Updated convenors</change>
            <change when="2009-11-30" who="CJR">Added updates from 2009 MM.</change>
            <change when="2007-04-22" who="CJR">Converted to P5</change>
            <change when="2004-02-19" who="syd">Made valid; separated out report on Nancy meeting to
                separate document.</change>
            <change when="2004-02-19" who="EdwardVanhoutte">creating XML/TeixLite document</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <p>The goal of the TEI Special Interest Group on Manuscripts is to bring together
                    users of the TEI who wish to improve the encoding strategies for marking up
                    transcriptions and editions of manuscript materials.</p>
                <list type="ordered">
                    <head>This SIG explores a range of issues common to editing manuscripts,
                        including:</head>
                    <item>how to handle time based encoding</item>
                    <item>how to record place based encoding</item>
                    <item>how to encode fragments</item>
                    <item>how to record codicology (the substance of the medium, ink stints, etc);
                        Robinson noted that the TEI already has mechanisms to record this, but it
                        needs to be better documented</item>
                    <item>issues of substitutions</item>
                    <item>issues of variation</item>
                    <item>to clarify the role of the critical apparatus tag set in manuscript
                        transcription </item>
                </list>
                <p>The group operates by means a mailing list and also has an area on the <ref
                        target="http://wiki.tei-c.org/index.php/SIG:MSS">TEI wiki</ref>. </p>
                <p>NEW: <ref target="http://www.tei-c.org/SIG/Manuscripts/genetic.html">Documents
                        and Genetic Criticism TEI Style</ref>.</p>
                <p>The SIG is convened by Stephen McCormick and Gerrit Brüning. The SIG runs a
                    mailing list, which you can join by visiting <ptr
                        target="http://listserv.brown.edu/tei-ms-sig.html"/></p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Recent Activities</head>
                <p> The Manuscript SIG sponsored the following activities during the 2009 TEI
                    Conference and Members' Meeting in Ann Arbor: <list>
                        <item>a panel "New Tools and Perspectives for Manuscript Editing", organised
                            by Amanda Gailey, with papers delivered by Elena Pierazzo, Jindrich
                            Marek, and Tanya Clement</item>
                        <item>a panel "Encoding Genetic Editions", organised by the SIG task force,
                            with presentations by Fotis Jannidis, Elena Pierazzo, Lou Burnard, and
                            Malte Rehbein</item>
                        <item>other papers and posters that cover manuscript related topics. e.g.
                            the Medieval Nordic Text Archive (Menota; Tone Merete Bruvik, and Odd
                            Einar Haugen), The St. Patrick's Confessio Hypertext Stack (Franz
                            Fischer), Digital Scholarly Editions of Letters and Correspondence (Bert
                            van Raemdonck), Wittgenstein's Nachlass in P5 (Tone Merete Bruvik, Alois
                            Pichler, and Vermund Olstad), the new TEI-EJ journal, and a rountable
                            discussion on "Trends to Watch in the TEI Community"</item>
                    </list> Abstracts of the presentations can be found here: <ptr
                        target="http://www.lib.umich.edu/spo/teimeeting09/program.html"/>. </p>
                <p>Furthermore, the annual SIG Business Meeting was held with more than a dozen
                    participants. Brief minutes can be found <ref target="MSSIG-2009.xml"
                    >here</ref>, while more detailed minutes can be found on the wiki: <ptr
                        target="http://wiki.tei-c.org/index.php/SIGMS_Minutes_20091114"/>. </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
